<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kristin Berry: GIS Portfolio Page on Kristin Berry&#39;s GIS Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://kree.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kristin Berry: GIS Portfolio Page on Kristin Berry&#39;s GIS Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kree.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Kristin Berry, a scientific software professional with some experience in GIS. I&amp;rsquo;m worked on projects ranging from small websites created to customer specifications to large image-processing software systesm with 15+ years of active development, and have an academic background in Physics and Earth, Atmospheric, and Plantary Sciences. I always enjoy learning new things and am always interested in new connections and oppurtunities. This site showcases primarily GIS projects created as part of the UWF GIS Certificate Program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can contact me by using the form below.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required.  Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Here is a a sampling of my GIS work:
  Ward 7 Schools, Washington DC   This map shows the schools in Ward 7 of Washington DC. Elementary, middle, and high schools are indicated by symbols of different size. The main feature of the map - Ward 7 - is a lighter color than the background of the rest of DC to create good figure/ground contrast.
  Map of Marathon, FL   Map of Marathon, Florida created by me using Adobe Illustrator, and the ArcGIS extension for Adobe Illustrator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>Here is my GIS-focused resume, available as a downloadable PDF: Resume</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
