<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS 4048 on Kristin Berry&#39;s GIS Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://kree.github.io/tags/gis-4048/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS 4048 on Kristin Berry&#39;s GIS Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 20:40:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kree.github.io/tags/gis-4048/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab 6 - Damage Assessment</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-08-08-gis-4048-lab-6-damage-assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 20:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-08-08-gis-4048-lab-6-damage-assessment/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, first we mapped Hurricane Sandy&amp;rsquo;s full path from Tropical Depression to Category 2 Hurricane, and then we assessed the damage that occurred in a small parcel on the coast of New Jersey, using images from before and after Sandy&amp;rsquo;s arrival.
To assess this damage, after setting up the pre-Sandy and post-Sandy images in mosaics, I intersected the New Jersey parcels feature class with the Study Area feature class to just get the parcels in the study area so that it was clear which parcels were examined for damage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab 5: Coastal Flooding</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-08-02-gis-4048-lab-5-coastal-flooding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-08-02-gis-4048-lab-5-coastal-flooding/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we examined various different ways of calculating coastal flooding. First, we looked at LAS (LIDAR) datasets for an area of New Jersey, pre and post Hurricane Sandy. Visible changes in the width of the barrier island (it seems to have expanded in places) and the altitude of certain areas decreased or increased.
Next, we looked at Storm Surge in New Jersey by examining areas of a DEM under the average storm surge of 2m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab 4 - Crime Analysis</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-26-gis-4048-lab-4-crime-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 21:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-26-gis-4048-lab-4-crime-analysis/</guid>
      <description>To calculate a kernel density hotspot map, we used the Kernel Density tool built in to ArcGIS Pro, and then filtered out all results below 3 times the mean to produce the following map:
To create a Moran&amp;rsquo;s I hotspot map, we first joined census tract information with the homicide points to get a count of homicides for each census tract. Then, we used the number of households per tract to get a per-household crime rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab 3 Visibility Analysis - ArcGIS training</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-17-gis-4048-lab-3-visibility-analysis-arcgis-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 21:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-17-gis-4048-lab-3-visibility-analysis-arcgis-training/</guid>
      <description>For lab this week, we took 4 online ArcGIS training courses, all about learning how to use the 3D side of ArcGIS.
1.) 3D Visualization using ArcGIS Pro:
The most useful part of this exercise for me was simply how to navigate 3D ArcGIS scenes by controlling the camera, panning, zooming, etc. I also didn&amp;rsquo;t realize it was possible to dock maps and scenes side-by-side and link them. This is very cool and useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab2 - Forestry and Lidar</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-gis-4048-lab2-forestry-and-lidar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 17:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-gis-4048-lab2-forestry-and-lidar/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, LIDAR data was used to generate a map of the tree canopy density for a region of Shenandoah National Park, Virginia. This area lies in the Blue Ridge Mountains and along the Appalachian Trail.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the National Park Service map for part of this area: https://www.nps.gov/shen/planyourvisit/upload/BigMeadows_RoadTrail.pdf !
Lidar data was provide in Lidar Point Cloud (LPC) format. This was used to create a DEM by filtering to include only ground points, and a DSM representing the canopy, which included only non-ground points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048/5100 - Lab 1 Least Cost Path Analysis and Corridor Analysis: Scenario 2</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-08-gis-4048-5100-lab-1-least-cost-path-analysis-and-corridor-analysis-scenario-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 21:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-08-gis-4048-5100-lab-1-least-cost-path-analysis-and-corridor-analysis-scenario-2/</guid>
      <description>For this section of Lab 1, a suitability assessment for property development was performed in an area of Southern Oregon. First, information provided about soil and land types via raster images were reclassified into rasters with cell values indicating suitability ratings for development. Next, suitability ratings were assigned to slope values, using information from a DEM. Following this, rasters were generated indicating the distance from rivers and roads in this study area and these were also reclassified to suitability ratings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048 - Lab 1 - Scenario 4: Coronado National Forest Black Bear Corridor Analysis</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-08-gis-4048-lab-1-scenario-4-coronado-national-forest-black-bear-corridor-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 19:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-08-gis-4048-lab-1-scenario-4-coronado-national-forest-black-bear-corridor-analysis/</guid>
      <description>For this section of the first Lab, &amp;ldquo;Scenario 4,&amp;rdquo; the most suitable or least-cost corridor for black bear movement was calculated between two protected areas of Coronado National Forest in Southern Arizona. Criteria included in the suitability calculation were: elevation, distance from roads, and land cover types. ArcGIS Pro was used to create Cost Distance surfaces from each Protected Area, and these were then combined using the Corridor tool to generate a single corridor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS 4048/5100 - About Me</title>
      <link>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-gis-4048-5100-about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 12:18:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kree.github.io/posts/2020-07-03-gis-4048-5100-about-me/</guid>
      <description>My name is Kristin. Applications in GIS (GIS 5100) is my second-to-last course (excluding the internship) in the GIS Certificate program at UWF. My experience in GIS prior to this program was limited. I work on image-processing software for the US Geological Survey, but the level of processing this software performs is usually done prior to importing images into ArcGIS or QGIS. I joined this program because I wanted to have a better background in GIS to further my knowledge and career.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
